JASIM UDDIN

Front End Software Engineer(2+ years of experience)
Thaka, Bangladesh

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript (ES6)
- Node.js
- HTML5
- CSS3

LIBRARIES & FRAMEWORKS

- React Tailwind CSS
- ReduxMaterial UI
- Next.js
- Sass/LESS

TOOLS & SOFTWARE

- MongoDB
- GitHub
- Docker
- Jira

EXPERIENCES

Front End Engineer | SEO Audit Agency

Dhaka, BD

Mar 2020 - Present

- Write modern, perform, and robust code for including new features in SAASbased software which is an SEO Service Software.
- Create React components to perform and visualize dynamic data by maintaining the SRP principle. Use Redux for manage state and data.
- Expend features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement.
- Designing and developing by collaborating with UI/UX team to include new features using React, Redux, and Python RESTful APIs.
- Launch new features on a weekly and monthly basis by uploading them on the server to using Docker & GitHub Actions.

Front End Developer | Stack Learner

Dhaka, BD

Apr 2021 - Jul 2021

- Worked on building new React components for the customer-facing web app which improved the time on page for the average user by 2 minutes.
- Worked within an agile team and helped prioritize and scope feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Design and developed applications using top-notch technologies like React, Redux, Next.js, TypeScript etc.

Web Developer (Front End) | Print Wizard

Dhaka, BD

Apr 2019 – Dec 2019

- Worked with a team of three designers to build a marketing website and ecommerce platform for Print Wizard, an ambitious venture originating.
- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new features development.

EDUCATIONS

- Computer Science And Engineering (2021-present) Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT). Possible competed date is 2023.
- (2015-2019) Diploma Engineering in Computer Technology Muslim Aid Institute Of Technology (MAIT), Jessore.

ABOUT ME

I'm a team player. I've 2+ years of experience working as a Front End Developer with diverse web technologies that mostly Front End and some of the Back End. Write perform and robust code for SaaS software by maintaining the SOLID class to make software designs more understandable, flexible, and maintainable.

Project management experience by including new features and testing the code using JavaScript testing frameworks like Mocha/Jest and uploading error-free code into the production server properly using Docker, GitHub Actions, etc.

I'm interested to work in a role that will allow me to design develop and implement client-side solutions in a highly engaging, collaborating, and constantly improving team. Also where I can work with various types of solutions and technologies that leading the world.

ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS

- Sound ethical background & presentation skills.
- Ability to work independently & as a team player
- Excellent interpersonal & communication skills.
- Endurance to work for long hour and pressure
- Strong motivation and commitment for work
- Quick learner and fast problem solver

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

BANGLA

LINKS

facebook.com/devjasim

stackoverflow.com

in <u>linkedin.com/in/devjasim</u>

github.com/devjasim

RECENT PROJECT

SEO Audit Software App.

https://app.seoaudit.software Technology: React, Redux, Python.

SEO Audit Software.

https://seoaudit.software/

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

PlanetHR.

https://planethrms.com

Technology: THML, CSS, WordPress